A Guide to the Sol and Virginia Wrenn family papers, 1815-2020
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Sol and Virginia Wrenn family papers, 1815-2020
The Library of Virginia
53169
18.13 cu. ft. (43 boxes)
Wrenn family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James Wrenn, Tarboro, North Carolina.
Biographical Information
James Solomon Wrenn, Jr., was born 10 September 1921 to James Solomon Wrenn, Sr. (1881-1960) and Mary Cochran Wrenn (1889-1984) of Emporia, Virginia. Sol Wrenn graduated from Greensville County High School in 1938. After attending Randolph-Macon College for two years, he transferred to the University of Southern California, graduating in 1942 with a degree in cinema. In World War II, Wrenn enlisted in the United States Navy and served as communications officer aboard the USS Planter. After the war, he served as an officer in the Naval Reserves, reaching the rank of lieutenant commander and serving as aide de camp to several Virginia governors. In 1946, Wrenn joined the Virginia Department of Education Film Productions Services and helped make over 100 films on Virginia history and nature. He retired in 1986. Wrenn was a charter member of the University Film and Video Association, as well as a charter member of the Crestwood Farms Residents Association and the Richmond Bonsai Society. He was an active member of the Bon Air Historical Society and Forest Hill Presbyterian Church. Wrenn married Virginia Elizabeth Wimer (1921-2017) 9 April 1949, and they had three children. Sol Wrenn died 29 March 2020, in Richmond, Virginia.
Virginia Elizabeth Wimer was born 8 October 1921 in Augusta County, Virginia, to Watt Lee Wimer (1889-1960) and Millie Malcom Wimer (1890-1976). Virginia Wimer graduated from Churchville High School in Augusta County, and attended Mary Baldwin College and Dunsmore Business School, both in Staunton, Virginia. She married Sol Wrenn (1921-2020) 9 April 1949 and they had three children. Virginia Wrenn was a founding member and trustee of the Crestwood Farms Residents Association and a founding member of the Richmond Bonsai Society. She was an active member of the Bon Air Historical Society, including 10 years as president. Wrenn was a member of the National Story League and the Richmond Story League, and sponsor of the Jolly Wrenn Bards as part of the Richmond Story League. She was a member of the Virginia Poetry Society and a distinguished member of the International Society of Poetry. An active member of Forest Hill Presbyterian Church, she taught classes on storytelling as a faith formation tool. Virginia Elizabeth Wimer Wrenn died 24 March 2017 in Richmond, Virginia, and is buried in Greenwood Memorial Gardens.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1815-2020, of James Solomon Wrenn, Jr. (1921-2020) and Virginia Elizabeth Wimer Wrenn (1921-2017) of Richmond, Virginia, consisting of autograph books, clippings, correspondence, directories, minutes, obituaries, photographs, scrapbooks, and other papers detailing their personal and professional lives and interests and providing insight into their community activities. Papers also include correspondence and other papers relating to members of the extended Wrenn family and the Wimer family.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in the following series
Series I: Sol and Virginia Wrenn Papers, 1947-2020
Series II: Sol Wrenn, Jr., Papers, 1934-2020
Series III: Virginia Wrenn Papers, 1921-2017
Series IV: Wrenn Family Papers, 1815-2006
Series V: Wimer Family Papers, 1894, 1907-1909
Contents List
- Sol and Virginia Wrenn Papers, 1947-2020., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 1-9)
  Series I: Sol and Virginia Wrenn Papers, 1947-2020, containing booklets, bulletins, cassette tapes, clippings, correspondence, greeting cards, negatives, obituaries, passenger lists, photographs, records, and other papers. Series deals with the Wrenns' personal lives and activities, as well as their activities as members of the Crestwood Farms Residents Association, Forest Hill Presbyterian Church, the Bon Air Historical Society, the Richmond Bonsai Society, and other historical and civic organizations.
  - Sol and Virginia Wrenn personal papers, 1947-2020., 2 boxes (Box 1-2)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, January-March 1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, April-May 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, June 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, July 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, August 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, September 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, October 1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, November 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, December 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, January 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, February 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, March 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, April 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, May 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, June 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, July 1948 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, August 1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, September 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, October 1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, November 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, December 1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, January 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, February 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wimer, March 1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letters, Sol Wrenn to Virginia Wrenn, June 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Honeymoon--Queen of Bermuda passenger list and diary and breakfast menu April 1949 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Honeymoon--The Gateway to Bermuda: a Pocket Guide, April 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - WRVA radio show--Win If You Can, 14 August 1950 (see also box 30) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1950, 1977, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wrenn family Christmas, 1955, 1963-1970 (see also box 31) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Sol and Ginny Wrenn 50th wedding anniversary, 9 April 1999 (see also box 31) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sol and Ginny Wrenn 50th wedding anniversary--Tides Inn (Irvington, Virginia), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Memorial services and funerals attended, 2004, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Obituaries for Virginia Wrenn and Sol Wrenn, 2017, 2020 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Wrenn home and Lake Page photographs (see also box 42, folder 1) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Wrenn family and Crestwood Farms photographic negatives (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Crestwood Farms Residents Association, 1969-2018., 3 boxes (Box 2-4)
    - Constitutions (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Officers and history, 1969, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Minutes and dues, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Directory, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Directory, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Directory, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Directory, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Handbook and directories, 1991, 1992, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Directories, 1999, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Directories, 2008, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Directory drafts and notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - President's (Virginia Wrenn) letter and drafts, March 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Easter sunrise services, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Easter sunrise services, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Easter sunrise services, 1991-2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Easter sunrise services, 2001-2010 (no 2005, 2007,2008) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Easter sunrise services, 2011-2018 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Easter sunrise services photographs, 1987, 2000, 2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Easter sunrise services papers, 2001, 2007, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Christmas caroling, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Christmas gathering photographs, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Picnics, 1972, 1981-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Picnic photographs, 1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Barbecues, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Community sale, 13 November 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Papers, 1980-2006, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Notes (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - HMK Corporation documents, 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence--HMK and rezoning, 1983-2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Clippings--HMK rezoning, 1984, 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Papers--HMK (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Crestwood Farms preconstruction photographs, November 1965 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Crestwood Farms photographs, March-April 1969 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Lake Page photographs and information (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Crestwood Elementary School, 1969-2018., 1 box (Box 4)
    - Lake Page Project, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Visits--photographs (see also box 42, folder 2) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Crestwood Presbyterian Church, 1966-1971., 1 box (Box 4)
    - Formation documents, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Membership directories, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Bulletins and worship, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Board of Deacons, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Steering committee notes, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Church rental of Crestwood Elementary School, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Financial records, 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Camp Hanover, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Women of the Church constitution, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence and general papers, 1968-1970 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Photographs, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Forest Hill Presbyterian Church, 1955-2006., 2 boxes (Box 4-5)
    - Directory, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Directory, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Directories, 1984, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Directories, 1991, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Church School Summer Series--Telling the Good News in Many Ways: Storytelling in Christian Education, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Church School Summer Series--Telling the Good News in Many Ways--Origins and Early Traditions of Storytelling by John Harrell (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Bulletins, newsletters, papers, and photographs, 1955-2006 (see also box 31 and box 41, folder 6) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bon Air Historical Society, 1979-2017., 3 boxes (Box 5-7)
    - Ginny Wrenn and the Bon Air Historical Society, 2017 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bylaws, 1982-1983, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Directories, 1983-2004 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Meeting minutes, 1979-2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Financial and insurance papers, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Membership applications, 1983-1989, 2000-2008 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Programs and events, 1985-2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence from president, 1985-1989, 2000, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Bon Air Tour: a Discerning Excursionist's Delight (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Bus tour of Old Bon Air (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Old Bon Air Historic Area, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Development in Bon Air, 1983, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Chesterfield County--parades, 1978, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence and papers, 1986-2007, undated (see also box 31) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1976-1989, 2008-2009 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Photographs (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Images of Old Bon Air (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Victorian Day, 19 May 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Victorian Day, 30 May 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Victorian Day, 7 May 1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Victorian Day, 12 May 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Victorian Day, 26 April 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Victorian Day, 2 May 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Victorian Day, 16 April 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Victorian Day, 22 April 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Victorian Day papers, ca. 1980s (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Victorian Day, 12 May 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Victorian Day, 20 April 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Victorian Day, 8 May 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Victorian Day, 8 May 1999 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Victorian Day, 13 May 2000 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Victorian Day, 12 May 2001 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Victorian Day, 11 May 2002 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Victorian Day, 10 May 2003 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Victorian Day, 8 May 2004 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Victorian Day, 7 May 2005 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Victorian Day, 13 May 2006 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Victorian Day, 12 May 2007 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Victorian Day, 10 May 2008 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Victorian Day general papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Victorian Day notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Victorian Day photographs, 1983-1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Victorian Day photographs, 1991, 1997, 2001, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Victorian Day photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Victorian Day--Ginny Wrenn president banners and Ginny Wrenn photograph board, ca. 1986-1989, 1997 (see box 43, folder 1) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Bon Air Community Association, 1979-2007., 1 box (Box 7)
    - Papers, 1979-2007 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bonsai, 1968-2008., 2 boxes (Box 7-8)
    - Virginia Bonsai Society, Capitol District, papers, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Capitol Area Bonsai Society photographs, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society--lifetime membership to Ginny and Sol Wrenn, 13 December 1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society bylaws, 1970, updated 1978, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society meeting minutes and related papers, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society membership lists and directories, 1986-1992, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society newsletters, 1990, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society--Potomac Bonsai Association newsletters and symposium, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society membership brochures (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society demonstrations, exhibits, lectures, 1984-1989, undated (see also box 41, folder 1) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society garden and flower shows (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society papers, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society scrapbooks, 1972-1990 (see boxes 33 and 34) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society photographs from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society photographs from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1981[?] (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society photographs from scrapbook 1 (box 33), undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society negatives from scrapbook 1 (box 33), undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society correspondence from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1978-1983 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society correspondence from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1985-1988, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society articles from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1974-1984, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society clippings from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1983-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society chrysathemum bonsai from scrapbook 1 (box 33) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society Sunny Slope Gardens papers from scrapbook 1 (box 33), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society papers from scrapbook 1 (box 33) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society notes from scrapbook 1 (box 33) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society photographs from John Naka visit scrapbook (gray volume, box 34), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society photographs, 1970-1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society bonsai workshop, Ikebana, photographs, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Richmond Bonsai Society picnic photographs, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Bonsai--Ginny Wrenn (see box 41, folders 2-3) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Bonsai--papers (see also box 31) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Bonsai--photographs (see also box 42, folder 3) (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Great Peanut Tour, 1988-2011., 2 boxes (Box 8-9)
    - Papers, 1988-2000 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1992-2006, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1992-1999 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 2001-2011, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Photographs, 1991, 1993, 1996, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Photographs, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Photographs, 2002-2006 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous., 1 box (Box 9)
    - Changes All Around I See, autobiography of Joseph B. Underwood (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Inspirational Poems for Christian Homes, by C. Clifford Hevener (see box 29) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield County Virginia: A History, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - The Common Glory: A Souvenir Program of the Symphonic Drama (Williamsburg, Va.), 1948 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - The Executive Mansion: Virginia (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Virginia, Virginia Historic Landmarks Commission, Spring, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Virginia's Capitol Square: Its Buildings and Its Monuments (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bon Air Christian Church history, June 2007 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1932, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Clippings--Richmond tornado of 13 June 1951, 14 June, 24 June 1951 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1954, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Clippings--Life After Death series, 3-5 December 1957 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1964, 1965, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1979, 1985-1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1985, 1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1991, 1992, 1998, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Cartoons (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous papers (see also box 31) (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Bon Air Village News and Far West End Press, January-May 2002 (transferred to newspaper collections) (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Sol Wrenn Papers, 1935-2020., Extent: 12 boxes. (Box 10-21)
  Series II: Sol Wrenn, Jr., Papers, 1934-2020, containing autograph books, catalogs, certificates, clippings, correspondence, diaries, financial records, invitations, journals, photographs, postcards, scrapbooks, yearbooks, and other papers detailing Sol Wrenn's youth, high school education, and college education at Randolph-Macon Collection and the University of Southern California, as well as his naval service aboard the USS Planter during World War II and as a Naval Reserve officer. Papers also describe his career in the Film Services Production Services branch of the Virginia Department of Education and his membership in the University Film and Video Association. Papers also highlight his activities and interests in organizations, including the Richmond Meteorology Society.
  - Correspondence and writings, 1934-1987., 2 boxes (Box 10-11)
    - Diaries, 1936-1938 (see box 32) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Inaugural invitation, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Autograph book, 20 January 1937 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook, 1938-1940 (see box 40) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, April-September 1941 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, October-December 1941 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, January-February 1942 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, March-May 1942 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, September 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, October-November 1942 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, December 1942 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, January-February 1943 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, March-April 1943 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, May-June 1943 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, July 1943 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, August-September 1943 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Correspndence, November 1943 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, December 1943 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, January-March 1944 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, May 1944 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, June 1944 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, July 1944 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, August 1944 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, September 1944 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, October 1944 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, November 1944 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, December 1944 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, April-May 1945 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, June 1945 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, July 1945 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, August 1945 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, September 1945 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, October-November 1945 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1987 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Collected writings (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Emporia, 1937-2009., 1 box (Box 11)
    - Greensville County and Emporia, pp. 18-21, from Virginia and the Virginia County, July 1951 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Industrial Sites and Economic Data: Emporia, Virginia, November 1955 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Main Street United Methodist Church Sesquicentennial Celebration, 1847-1997, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Clippings on Emporia, 1937-2009 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Clippings on the great flood of 1940 in Emporia and Greensville County (information and photographs supplied by Sol Wrenn), 1963-2005 (see also box 31 and box 41, folder 20) (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Emporia photographs (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Sol Wrenn--information on home movies of Emporia (movies transferred to visual studies) (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Emporia Elementary School and Greensville County High School, 1934-2004., 1 box (Box 12)
    - Emporia Elementary School newspaper, 6 April 1934 (copy--original transferred to newspaper collections) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sol Wrenn's diploma, Greensville County High School, 31 May 1938 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Riparian, Greensville County High School yearbooks, 1935-1936 (see box 28, folders 1-2) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Greensville County High School newspaper, The Green and Gold, 1937-1938 (copies--originals tranferred to the newspaper collections) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Greensville County High School Class of 1938 papers, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Greensville County High School Class of 1938 alumni lists, 1968, 1988 (see also box 41, folder 5) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Greensville County High School Class of 1938 alumni correspondence and papers, 1988-2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Greensville County High School Class of 1938 alumni reunion photographs, 1988, 1996, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Randolph-Macon College, 1938-2006., 1 box (Box 12)
    - Randolph-Macon College catalog, 1938-1939 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Yellow Jacket, Randolph-Macon College yearbooks, 1939-1940 (see box 28) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Phi Kappa Sigma fraternity certificate, 25 February 1939 (see box 35, folder 1) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Ann Rutherford photographs, 15 October 1939 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Randolph-Macon vs. Hampden-Sydney football program, 13 November 1948 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Old Grads Weekend and Class of 1942, 29 May 1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Old Grads and Class of 1956 reunion scrapbook, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 15)